

Rachana K Prakash

FRONTEND ENGINEER

A Frontend Engineer with 4+ years of comprehensive expertise in Angular and Javascript. I can create user interfaces that are clean, accessible, efficient, and that provide an excellent user experience. I have experience working alone and with teams ranging from 3 to 8.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SYNCRON SOFTWARE INDIA PRIVATE LIMITED SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Aug 2021 - Oct 2022

- <u>Technologies</u>: Angular 11, HTML, CSS, Typescript, Angular Material, Responsive Web Design, AG Grid.
- Engineered pixel-perfect screens with optimized user experience.
- Collaborated with the Uptime Product Team members to implement 6 new feature developments.
- Part of the Core CSX Design Team Developing an application for clients and its users with a code coverage
- of 90%.
- Assessed UX and UI designs for technical feasibility.

INFRRD, INC.

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

May 2021 - July 2021

- <u>Technologies</u>: Angular 6-7, HTML, CSS, Typescript, Angular Material, Responsive Web Design.
- Took ownership of deployments and PR reviews.
- Responsible for training freshers in UI.
- Involved in requirement analysis and design discussions.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jul 2018 - May 2021

- Built reusable UI components for Homegenius.
- Built responsive screens with a keen eye for design, ensuring perfect adherence to design specification.
- Solely responsible for creating a Beta Brokerage application based on Homegenius.
- Built the UI of a document processing application for our Product Team; configured according to each client's
- needs.
- Mentored new UI Developers to get them up to speed on team targets and responsibilities.

CERNER HEALTHCARE SOLUTIONS PVT. LTD DELIVERY CONSULTANT

Nov 2015 - Feb 2018

- Performed in-depth Functional Testing, assigned and prioritized events, detected numerous defects for 5+ solutions.
- Performed Automation Testing for multiple clients and solutions thereby reducing manual work by 60%.

NOTABLE PROJECTS

Game Hub June 2023 – July 2023

- Showcases a collection of games and has functional features to filter/find games.
- <u>Technologies</u>: React 18, HTML, Typescript, ChakraUl, Responsive Web Design.

Marvel News Mar 2021

- A simple news media application based on Marvel with a private gallery view consisting of images fetched from a Marvel API.
- <u>Technologies</u>: Angular 15, HTML, CSS, Typescript, Angular Material, Responsive Web Design.

Homegenius Sep 2018 – July 2021

- A real estate transaction management system for a virtual brokerage. It focuses on discovering, purchasing or selling real estate.
- <u>Technologies</u>: Angular 6-7, HTML, CSS, Typescript, Angular Material, Responsive Web Design.

CONTACT

rachana.prakash91@gmail.com

Bengaluru, India

LinkedIn

GitHub

Portfolio

EDUCATION

Christ University, Bengaluru MCA, 2013-2106

SKILLS

Proficient In

Angular

Javascript

React

Typescript

CSS3

HTML5

Git Rxis

Ngrx

Jest

Karma

Bootstrap

Tailwind

ChakraUl

LANGUAGES

English, Kannada, Hindi Full Professional Proficiency